(escalator clicks)
As I go toward the escalator,
a young fellow and a girl get on ahead of me.
Her dress, her stockings, are skin tight.
She places one foot above the other
upon the steps,
and her behind assumes its position.
The young man looks all about.
He appears worried.
He looks at me.
I look away.
No, you see I'm looking away.
I am not looking at your girl's behind.
Don't worry, I respect everything.
The flowers that grow.
The birds.
(birds chirp)
The sky.
(plane engine roars)
The universe.
I sense that the young man feels better,
and I'm glad for him.
I know his problems.
The girl has a mother and a father,
and maybe a brother,
and undoubtedly a bunch of relatives.
She likes to dance and flirt,
(loud music blares)
and she likes to go to movies.
And sometimes she chews gum
and talks at the same time.
And she enjoys the dumbest TV shows.
And she thinks she's an actress.
Goodbye Rick, God bless you.
And she doesn't always look good.
And she has a terrible temper.
I hate you!
And sometimes she goes crazy
and she can talk for hours on the telephone.
Oh my god, and that's an awful car.
I told you not to.
And she wants to go
to Europe every summer.
And she wants to own a Mercedes.
And she's in love with Mel Gibson.
And her mother is a sneak drunk.
And her father secretly hates blacks,
browns, and yellows.
And she snores
(loud snoring)
And is also cold in bed.
(man moaning)
And she has a guru,
a guy who met Christ in the desert in 1978.
And she wants to be a skydiver.
And she's unemployed and gets migraine headaches
every time she eats sugar, or cheese.
I watch him take her up the further escalator,
his arm protectively about her waist.
Thinking he's lucky.
Thinking he's macho.
Thinking that nobody in the world
has what he has, and he's right.
Terribly, terribly right.
Holding onto that batch of intestines,
bladder, lungs, tetra zone
flagellate protozoa
sulfur, carbon dioxide, phelem, and phlegm.
Lotsa luck.
("Who Do You Love" by Bo Diddley)