I do think about bipolar as part of who I am
It defines your outlooks at certain points
and just completely takes over
who you are and how you see things.
Hiya
Hello
I live in a three bedroom house in London
which is fortunate because it's cheap
and it’s the only way I can afford
to live in the city
We’ve turned our living room into a fourth bedroom
so we have no communal space
so I do everything in my bedroom
I watch TV on my laptop
I work, I sleep, I eat
I drink, I rest, everything.
It needs to be my haven
because it’s the only space I have
but there are large periods of time
where I just can’t look after it
and during that time it becomes the opposite
a hazard, a risk, a danger
and it just gets really messy
and I don’t know how it happens
and I never see it coming
but it just always, always does.
I suppose I sort of think about it
as if there are loads of different versions of me
the rational Ellice, which is the real one
and then the mania and the low
and then the extreme versions of those
and when you slip in to one or the other
you just lose sight of the rational.
It feels like weight
like my legs gain three stone
and it’s difficult to move when I want to.
It feels like a hand
pressing against my back
so I spend a lot of time
trying to stretch it out
but I can’t really do anything about it.
You don’t have the concentration and the focus
to really know that you’re in something at the time
to find the words to describe it.
And when you’re out of it it feels so alien.
It’s an extreme.
When you’re bipolar and you go really low
it’s nice to go high.
It’s just when it goes too far
and you can’t stop your hands from moving
and you can’t shut up and you can’t stop talking.
It can be horrid.
When I’m down it’s about my self worth
It’s asking me who I am?
What I'm doing?
What I’m doing with my life?
Just telling me that I’m shit
just pretty fucking shit.
It goes so quickly from one to the other
and there are days when I feel really good
and I have really high self esteem
and I feel like I’m just a normal person.
And then it’s only a day later
when I’ve properly stabled out
that I realise
I was being delusional.
I’ve been sat in a valley between
the rubbish and the clothes for weeks
just staring out at the mess.
Orange juice bottles, dried orange peel
wine bottles, sweet wrappers, crisp wrappers
just crap, crap, crap, crap.
I think it’s
a really dynamic thing
and it’s really subjective
so I don’t think there are really
stock things you can say about it.
And I’m still getting to grips with
how it manifests for me.
And the clothes at the end of my bed
a pile of dirty and clean.
I will sort through them
and I will reorganise them
and I will put them away so that for a while
it’s tidy and things will just be good for a bit.
I think you have to accept it
and accept everything knowing it will pass
and then most probably repeat
because that’s just the way
to be the kindest to yourself.