(Multiple voices)
Growing up...
Growing old...
(child)
Growing older is
like a line
because it never stops
(child)
It's actually changing,
your body changes you.
You get bigger,
your blood
changes actually,
and your mind
actually changes.
(child)
It's funner seeing
the whole world
when you grow up.
You get to explore
more things.
See more things
you never seen.
(child)
Cycles,
It cycles again and again
I don't know,
I just want to be six
(father)
This is the
hardest step!
This is the hardest step
to getting to grow!
You can do it!
You can do it.
Almost.
Just a little
farther!
There you go!
Good job!
(claps)
The first three
months of her life,
she couldn't
do anything
on her own.
I'm looking forward
to her learning
to bicycle.
Still a few years out.
(father)
You got it?
(son)
No, no, no, no, no!
(child)
I just want to be really good
at riding a bike.
(father)
You got it?
(son)
Keep going.
Keep going? You got it?
(child)
If I got to fast,
I'll just fall.
If I go to slow,
it would just... no
(father)
Pay attention,
pay attention
Way to go Sebastian,
alright!
(Claps)
Way to go, my man!
(child)
Not all people produce babies
Um, boys don't produce babies
Um, I still don't understand why
boys don't produce babies
'Cause why  not boys?
(mother)
When she was first born,
She was kind of this blob that
didn't really do much
Like she just kind of laid there
and cried and ate and pooped,
and that was it.
All of a sudden,
it seemed like overnight,
it was like "oh she
can actually control her body!"
(child)
I really wanna meet
my biology mom,
because I want to know
where I came from
(girl)
I don't want to become
a super old lady.
I'm not going to use a cane,
and my hair is not going
to turn white
I'll dye it brown
(coach)
And jump!
(child)
I wanna get older fast
so I can go to the Olympics
(coach)
One, two, three, out!
Nice!
(claps)
(child)
I'm so scared!
(laughs)
I've never went this
high before!
(child)
I don't want to be a grown up
because....
it's boring!
(child)
I have to clean
the living room,
I have to sweep
the balcony,
(child)
Set the table,
Vacuum the living
room floor,
(child)
Put the dishes in
the dishwasher,
(child)
And taking out
the trash cans.
My brother is a
bad vacuumer.
I do not think my brother
is going to be a good grown up.
(teenage girl)
I feel like younger
siblings kind of grow up faster
because they see stuff their
older siblings are doing,
and they're like
"oh, I want to do that!"
(child)
My relationship with me
and my brother
is probably not so good.
We fight a lot.
(child)
Siblings can be annoying.
My sister's crazy.
(child)
We used to fight
less, but now we're
fighting more,
which is more
fun, actually.
(teenage boy)
Well, my brother just,
he's just like...
(child)
He plays the
worst music.
( ♪♪♪ )
(teacher)
That range should
be good. And stop!
Okay. So we'll go
over each part,
with the gong
starting first
(child)
I'm not really that nervous but,
I'm still a little bit
(child)
Because I don't want
to go to school
(teacher)
So today we are
talking about
parts of a leaf
(students)
Fourths
(teacher)
Fourths.
And this a
family of?
(student)
Fifth!
(teacher)
Triangle. So
that's a
triangle
What is the name
of the country that
we live in?
(student)
California!
( ♪♪♪ )
(teacher)
You can also use your fingers
to blend it in, if you want.
(child)
In fourth grade you
have to follow more directions,
and you can't make
that much noise, and you can't
put your elbows on the table,
and put her hands on your face.
You have to be more serious.
(child)
Um, I can meet new friends,
and ones I forgot
and remember them again
(man)
What happens at school
influences what happens at home,
and what happens at home,
influences what happens
at school.
And uh, whatever that
experience is,
you've got to hold to the things
that are true that matter most
You keep those as the constants,
and then learn how to work
through the rest.
(child)
When I'm 16,  I want to
be able to drive
(child)
Yeah. I would to
drive my own car
(child)
Maybe when I am older and pass
my driver's test, maybe.
(child)
But now I can't
because I am only 11.
(school bells rings)
(teenage girl)
As a freshman I didn't really
know what was going on
with anything
(teenage boy)
You have way more things
to do. You have to remember
your classes,
You have to remember
where they are.
(teenage girl)
You have to remember
all your homework
(teacher)
Don't worry about this
worksheet just yet.
We'll talk about it in
a little bit
(woman)
I remember being like a
freshman in high school and
seeing the seniors,
and being like, "wow, they are
so old and I can't wait to get
to that point"
(teenage boy)
Uh, it's not too bad.
Just, a lot of work
I don't want to do
(teenage girl)
I'm lazy and I procrastinate
And I feel like I'm going to be
in college longer than
other people
(boy)
Calculus, one B.
Integral Calculous,
macroeconomics, physics.
The green
chemistry class
Environment science class and
all my math classes.
My first day at college was
about two years ago.
And I'm eleven years old.
(sister screams)
I don't think there
is much of a correlation
between how big your
body is and what your
mind can do.
(man)
After a life through a
system of public school,
into college, I'm not in a
program right now
and it's sort of up to me
to make my own program
for the rest of my life,
and I'm at such a germinal
stage in that process.
I can't confidently say that
I am all grown up just yet
( ♪♪♪ )
(teenage girl)
I feel like I'm an adult -
me turning 15.
I waited a long time.
I feel like people see me
older, and trust me more.
When I'm a junior, I'm looking
forward to prom,
getting to wear a long dress
that's fancy and expensive
for no reason, really.
(minister)
We celebrate the union
of your hearts, your minds
(bride)
Here we go.
In my mind,
I had it set in that
I don't ever
want to marry,
I don't want
any of that, but,
I guess you meet
someone that
makes you change
your mind.
And so we're here.
(minister)
Everyone searches for
one special person
that they can share
their lives with,
The other half who makes
them whole.
(son)
It won't connect, daddy.
(father)
Yup, this one
connects, see?
Here, I'll show you.
(father)
It's a little tough
in the getting,
and then it get's easier
as you, you know,
establish a rhythm, and you
have your patterns and -
we've successfully avoided
going to court.
Often you can't work it out
on your own.
If you could,
you probably wouldn't be getting divorced
in the first place,
(laughs)
right?
This one has a different
connector, doesn't it?
Ow! Head butt.
Go!
But, I think the
biggest challenge
is just the distance.
There's a lot of
chauffeuring back and forth
There we go!
(man)
I've had custody of her since
she was seven years old.
And I've always, um, wanted
to fufill her dreams.
Most people are so focused
on getting old
I wanna drive.
I wanna drink.
I wanna move out,
I wanna get away from you.
I wed my wife
to become young.
And I think it takes all your
life to become young.
So I think getting old,
and aging,
I'm not going to buy it.
(woman)
I feel like I'm
100 years old.
One, two, three,
four, five,
six, seven, eight,
nine, ten.
(woman)
They say most like he was
going to be blind and deaf
One, two, three,
four, five,
six, seven, eight,
nine, ten.
And they say he was
going to be mute,
based on the brain
damage the he has.
Give me your hand.
One, two, three,
four, five,
six, seven, eight,
nine, ten.
Okay, next.
I'm going to be
here for him.
I'm his mom.
So there was not an option for
me to...
just, give up.
High thighs.
Ready?
(woman)
My mother -
she is optimistic
in a way
that's like, almost
annoying.
But actually,
I think it's the
thing that has
allowed me
to keep going,
when I really
didn't see any
way to go.
You out of water?
Yes.
Cold water.
(woman)
My mom was my compass
in my life.
As soon as I got
that phone call,
I feel like I aged 15 years.
I still walk out of a room, and
I'm gonna call my mom,
like, about to
dial her number,
and then it's like,
that reality of, like,
"oh you can never talk
to her again",
and you're really
on your own.
And that person that
has always been there,
and knows you the
best, and like,
loved you
unconditionally,
is no longer
in existence.
(man reading in
foreign language)
(man)
Yes, I have
one daughter.
She's in her
forties now, uh,
I love her dearly.
I just - we don't have
much in common anymore.
So, I have to deal
with that.
And it's going to be
that way 'til the end
(singing)
Through a blueberry hill
(child)
I wanna get really old,
like an old man,
so I don't have
to go work,
and I can just sit down
and be lazy.
(man)
It's like, being a
grownup sounds final.
(laughs)
I don't want it
to end, you know?
I want to
keep growing.
Maybe I never
grew up.
I wanna put on my
tombstone, you know,
he's stayed alive
'til the end.
(man)
My father is in the
mid-stages of Alzheimer's.
I come home at night,
make sure the things are off,
TV's off, helping to
change his diaper.
I feel that he's turning into
that one-year-old.
And, life is very fragile.
You have to accept it.
I hope I will die in a very
uneventful way.
Every night, I come give my
father a kiss.
And I say goodnight to him.
And, knowing that, if he's gonna
die, I hope he dies this way.
(Elderly woman
speaking foreign language)
(woman)
Growing up is like,
your reflection in a mirror
becoming clearer,
and crisper,
as time goes by.
(woman)
It would be a slinky.
That's what growing up
is for me.
It can just sit there
in a stack,
until it's put
into motion.
And once it's
put into motion,
it flops over itself,
but it's
making progress.
So it's a
different experience
every time it contracts
and unfolds,
and contracts
and does these leaps
on its journey.
(man)
Growing up is like
driving on the freeway
in that most of the time
you want to get through
it pretty quickly,
and most of the
time you don't.
But, at the end of the day,
you're probably going to get
to your destination.
(woman)
It's like somebody gave
me this huge atlas.
There aren't really any
instructions, like you're just
going to open this,
and maybe you're going to see
some things that you like.
And, maybe you're going to go
down the wrong path
and no one is really going
to stop you
and then when you get to the end
of that path,
you're going to figure out you
that you like, got something
out of it.
(woman)
To flower, that's my
idea of growth.
You come out
with yourself.
And I don't want you to
tell me what flower
you picked.
I want to witness
the flower you made.
(man)
You start learning
how to move
and you're like,
"oh, I think I got it,
I think I got it",
and then, uh,
and then you
get punched in the face.
Four months later, and you
learn how to throw out your
first combination,
and you get one jab in and
you get punched in the face.
As long as you can take
that punch,
and then you just realize,
ok, that was cool.
Let's keep going.
(woman)
I think that I would
pick a nautilus
I think that, they don't ever
really stop growing.
I don't think people ever really
stop growing up.
I don't think you're ever
really a grown up.
(girl)
Crazy but fun.
It's like a
rollercoaster, it takes
a lot of guts.
(woman)
It's the things you
can't quantify
(child)
It would probably
be a circle
(man)
It's a lot of things I find
now that I'm older
I keep revisiting.
(woman)
A metamorphosis.
All encompassing
and round
(child)
Because it never stops.